

SAMUELE FANTINI SENIOR MANAGER at BearingPoint

CONTACT



ADDRESS

Via Ampere, 20131 Milan, Italy



PHONE

+39 334 66 89 845



EMAIL

samuele.fantini.sf@gmail.com



DATE OF BIRTH

10 March 1985

LANGUAGES

Italian

English

PROFILE

I am a Senior Manager at PwC Advisory Italy working for the "Consumer Market" industry with an extensive experience in managing complex projects for international companies. Over the years, I have gained a broad knowledge by handling several innovative engagements for major players in the market. I have a proactive approach in dealing with business and digital transformations, with particular focus on operating model and organizational redesign for international companies. I am a hard-working innovative person who enjoys challenging himself every day in the right working environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 - TODAY SENIOR MANAGER at Bearing Point. Responsible for business development, project and resource management within Consumer Goods & Retail Industry through business and digital transformations for International companies.



2016 - 2022 **SENIOR MANAGER at PWC** : Responsible for managing business and digital transformations for international "Consumer Market" companies in order to define and execute process, organization, and systems enhancements.

Confident in managing teams, developing business, managing pipeline, building value proposition, handling negotiation and project economics, creating and executing workshops.

WORLDWIDE MERCHANDISER at BOTTEGA VENETA: Drive budget allocation, review and approve regional merchandising 2015 - 2016 plans. Support planning model transformation and its deployment from both functional and organizational prospective. Support the brand in harmonizing the internal processes, while building a "common ground" with other brands of the group.

CONSULTANT at accenture: Built a deep knowledge of planning processes for international companies within the "Fashion & 2011 - 2015 Luxury" industry. Skilled in business process optimization from the collection of strategic requirements till final deployment including change management activities. Competent in main project management activities such as project estimation, resource planning, management of economics, project monitoring and control.

BUSINESS ANALYST at IBM: Analyze the competition to address new products and software solutions in the market. Prepare and 2010 - 2011 actively share of "demo presentations" and "proof of concepts" to clients. Support marketing activities such as event organization, market analysis and strategy implementation. Monitor and control weekly forecasting previews. Focus on two main areas of business: "Business Process Management" and "Supply Chain Management".

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITA' DI MODENA E REGGIO EMILIA UNIMORE 2005 - 2011 Master degree in Industrial Engineering

LINKOPING UNIVERSITY (SWEDEN) 2009 - 2010 Innovation Management (Exchange student)

YALE SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT 2023 - 2023 Leadership Program



CERTIFICATIONS

- PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL (PMP)
- SCRUM MASTER (CSM)
- PROFESSIONAL COACH
- ANAPLAN MODEL BUILDER L2



